Guide to Columbia University Catalogs, etc. Cubb.00166
Cubberley Education Library
Columbia University (formerly Columbia College)
1861-1979
Cubberley Education Library
Cubb.00166
1872 item(s)
Located in New York City. Incorporated in 1754 as King's College. Incorporated by New York State in 1784 as Columbia College. Rechartered 1810. In 1896 the Trustees voted to change the name to Columbia University in the City of New York and to designate the School of Arts as Columbia College. Signed agreement with Barnard College in 1898. See also the finding aid for Barnard College.
New York (State)
- Columbia College (New York), 1861-1896; 63 item(s) Catalogs for 1861/62, 1869/70, 1871/72, 1876/77, 1891/92 Catalog for Academic Department 1876/77 Handbooks for 1878, 1888/89 Bound together with label "Registers": Handbooks for 1890/91-1893/94 Bound together with label "Registers": Catalogs for 1894/95-1895/96
  - Annual report of the president of Columbia College, 1868-1895; 14 item(s) Annual reports for 1868-1873 bound together with miscellaneous publications. Separately: 1880-1885, 1888 Report of Acting President 1889 Bound together: 1890, 1892-94 Bound with University Reports: 1895
  - The bar: its ancient fame and impending perils: a sermon preached before the graduating class of the Law School of Columbia College, May 13, 1866; 1 item(s) Bound with Annual reports
  - An address delivered before the graduating class of the Law School of Columbia College, May 19, 1869; 1 item(s) Bound with Annual reports
  - Address of Frederick A. P. Barnard, LL.D., [1870]; 1 item(s) Bound with annual reports. Address to the American Association for the Advancement of Science
  - Lecture on water delivered before the American Institute of the city of New York by C. F. Chandler, January 20, 1871; 1 item(s) Bound with Annual reports
  - Analysis of some statistics of collegiate education: a paper read before the trustees of Columbia College, January 3, 1870; 1 item(s) Bound with Annual reports
  - Modern industrial progress and the influences accelerating its march by Frederick A. P. Barnard, 1872; 1 item(s) Bound with Annual reports
  - A sermon preached before the graduating class of the Law School of Columbia College by Horatio Potter, May 12, 1872; 1 item(s) Bound with Annual reports.
  - College of Physicians and Surgeons, 1862-1894; 18 item(s) Annual catalog for 1862/63, 1872-1873, 1876, 1878-1881, 1884-1890 Circular of information for 1891/92-1893/94
  - Instruction for Graduates, 1880; 1 item(s)
- Columbia University, 1891-1979; 1809 item(s) Bound with catalogs under Columbia College: Catalog for 1896/97. Bound together with label of "Columbia College Registers": Catalogs for 1897/98-1899/1900 Bound together: Catalogs for 1900/01 & 1901/02 Catalog for 1902/03 Bound together: Catalogs for 1903/04 & 1904/05 Bound together: Catalogs for 1905/06 & 1906/07 Catalog for 1907/08 Bound together 1908/09 & 1909/10 Catalogs for 1910/11-1944/45
  - Entrance Examinations and Admissions, 1900-1937; 49 item(s) Announcements for 1916/17-1936/37
    Examinations.
    - Entrance Examinations, 1900-1904; 28 item(s) Bulletins for 1900, 1903, 1904
      - Entrance Examination in..., September, 1903; 25 item(s) Exam questions for Botany, Chemistry, English, French (Elementary, Intermediate, Advanced), German (Elementary, Intermediate), Elementary Greek (5 versions), Elementary History (4 versions), Elementary Latin (5 versions), Mathematics, Physiography, Spanish, and Zoology.
  - Columbia University. Columbia College, 1903-1976; 55 item(s) Announcements for 1903/04-1905/06, 1914/15, 1916/17-1917/18, 1920/21-1951/52, 1953/54-1962/63, 1964/65-1965/66, 1969/70, 1973/74-1976
    - Report of the Dean of Columbia College, 1925-1961; 7 item(s) Report for 1925-1928, 1931, 1947, 1960/61
  - Faculties of Political Science, Philosophy, and Pure Science, 1897-1957; 95 item(s) Announcements for 1899/1900; 1902/03-1904/05; 1907/09-1908/10; 1913/14-1914/15, 1916/17-1917/18, 1919/20, Graduate Announcements for 1921/22-1946/47
    - School of Pure Science, 1897-1898; 1 item(s)
    - Political Science, 1905-1947; 29 item(s)
      - History, Economics and Public Law courses offered by the Faculty of Political Science, 1905-1924; 8 item(s) Announcements for 1905/07-1907/09, 1913/14, 1916/17-1917/18, 1919/20, 1922/23-1923/24
      - History, Economics, Public Law, and Social Science, 1924-1941; 15 item(s) Announcements for 1924/25-1933/34, 1935/36-1938/39, 1940/41
      - History, Economics, Public Law and Sociology, 1941-1946; 5 item(s) Bulletins for 1941/42-1945/46
      - History, Economics, Public Law, Sociology and Anthropology, 1946-1947; 1 item(s) Bulletin for 1946/47
    - Faculty of Political Science, 1947-1957; 8 item(s) Announcements for 1947/48-1948/49, 1950/51, 1952/53-1956/57
    - Faculty of Philosophy, 1947-1957; 8 item(s) Announcements for 1947/48-1951/52, 1954/55-1956/57
    - Faculty of Pure Science, 1947-1957; 10 item(s) Announcements for 1947/48-1956/57
    - Report of the Dean of the Faculties of Political Science, Philosophy, and Pure Science, 1935-1937; 2 item(s) Reports for 1935, 1937
  - Schools of Mines, Engineering and Chemistry, 1896-1973; 96 item(s) School of Mines, School of Chemistry, School of Engineering, School of Architecture General Information for 1900/01 School of Mines, School of Chemistry, School of Engineering General Information for 1903/04 Announcements for 1907/08-1908/09,1911/12, 1915/16-1917/18. 1919/20-1928/29 New requirements for admission 1912/13 Professional Course in Industrial Engineering 1920/21
    - School of Mines, 1896-1901; 2 item(s) Announcement for 1896/97 Course in Metallurgy announcement 1900/01
    - School of Engineering and Applied Science, 1903-1973; 44 item(s) Bulletins for 1962/63, 1964/65-1965/66, 1967/68, 1972/73
      Engineering schools
      - Study and research in Electrical Engineering & Computer Science at Columbia University, [1970s]; 1 item(s)
      - School of Engineering, 1903-1957; 38 item(s) Courses in Mechanical Engineering announcement for 1903/04 Course in Electrical Engineering announcement for 1904/06 Civil, Electrical and Mechanical Engineering, Engineering Drafting announcement for 1906/07 Highway Engineering announcement for 1911/12 Bulletins for 1929/30, 1931/32-1936/37, 1938/39-1943/44, 1945/46-1947/48, 1949/50-1961/62
        - New Advanced Course in Engineering, [1914]; 1 item(s)
        - The Engineer and the University, 1921; 1 item(s)
        - Interim announcement of undergraduate and graduate courses in the School of Engineering covering present navy V-12 engineer specialist and civilian programs, and tentative post-war offerings for civilian and ex-service students, 1944; 1 item(s)
        - Engineering: graduate courses offered in the late afternoon and evening and on Saturday morning, 1948-1949; 1 item(s)
        - The School of Engineering in commemoration of the seventy-fifth anniversary of the establishment of Engineering Education at Columbia University, 1940; 1 item(s)
    - Division of Chemistry, 1905-1947; 30 item(s) Announcements for 1905, 1913/14, 1916/17-1917/18, 1919/20, 1921/22-1923/24, 1925/26-1946/47
  - Program in the Arts, 1904-1966; 33 item(s) Bulletins for 1958/59-1959/60, 1961/62-1965/66
    Art schools
    - Department of Fine Arts, 1904-1934; 14 item(s) Announcement for 1904/05, 1908/09, 1925/26-1933/34 Graduate course in Art and Archaeology announcement for 1928/29, 1930/31-1931/32
    - Division of Fine Arts and Archaeology, 1934-1937; 3 item(s) Announcements for 1934/35-1936/37
    - Division of Fine Arts, Archaeology, and Music, 1937-1947; 9 item(s) Announcements for 1937/38-1944/45, 1946/47
    - School of Painting and Sculpture, 1948-1952; 2 item(s) Announcements for 1948/49, 1951/52
  - School of Dental and Oral Surgery, 1913-1973; 84 item(s) Announcements for 1923/24-1924/25, 1927/28-1951/52, 1954/55-1966/67
    Dental schools
    - College of Dental and Oral Surgery of New York, 1913-1923; 6 item(s) Annual announcements for 1913/14, 1915/16-1916/17, 1918/19, 1922/23
      - Courses in Oral Hygiene for training women as dental hygienists, 1922-1923; 1 item(s) Announcement for 1922/23
    - Report of the Dean of the School of Dental and Oral Surgery, October 8, 1932; 1 item(s)
    - Postgraduate Programs in Dental Specialities, 1947-1972; 23 item(s) Bulletin for 1971/72
      - Postgraduate Courses for Dentists, 1947-1971; 22 item(s) Bulletins for 1947/48-1968/69, 1970/71
    - Courses for Dental Hygienists, 1927-1973; 39 item(s) Announcements for 1937/38-1959/60, 1961/62-1962/63, 1965/66-1967/68, 1972/73
      - Courses in Oral Hygiene, 1927-1937; 10 item(s) Announcements for 1927/28-1936/37
  - Division of Geology, Geography, and Mineralogy, 1913-1939; 22 item(s) Announcements for 1913/14, 1916/17-1917/18, 1919/20, 1921/22-1938/39
  - Division of Ancient and Oriental Languages, 1916-1947; 28 item(s) Announcements for 1916/17-1917/18, 1919/20, 1921/22-1944/45, 1946/47
  - Division of Biology, 1916-1947; 29 item(s) Announcements for 1916/17-1917/18, 1919/20, 1921/22-1946/47
  - Graduate School of Business, 1917-1969; 44 item(s)
    - School of Business, 1917-1949; 29 item(s) Announcements for 1917/18, 1922/23, 1925/26-1945/46, 1947/48-1948/49
      - Summary of Graduate and Undergraduate Courses, [1924]; 1 item(s) Summary rec'd Feb. 20, 1924 no date on publication.
      - Classes in Business Given in the Afternoon and Evening University Extension, 1932-1934; 2 item(s) Bulletins for 1932/33-1933/34
      - Courses in Business Summer Session, 1935; 1 item(s) Bulletin for 1935
    - Graduate School of Business, 1949-1969; 16 item(s) Announcements for 1949/50, 1951/52, 1953/54-1963/64, 1966/67, 1968/69
      - The Graduate School of Business report for the year 1965-1966 by Courtney C. Brown, Dean "Fiftieth Anniversary Observations", 1 item(s)
  - Summer Session, 1900-1975; 90 item(s) Announcements for 1900-1902, 1904-1918, 1920-1928, 1931-1956 Bulletins for 1957-1970, 1975 Posters for 1934, 1936 Preliminary Announcement for 1944 Courses in the Social Studies for 1927-1937, 1939 Courses in Chemistry, Mathematics, and Physics for 1931, 1934-1939
  - University Extension, 1915-1946; 20 item(s) Announcement for 1922/23 Bulletins for 1922-1923, 1930/31, 1940/41-1945/46
    - Professional Accounting: Evening program of studies leading to the 120 point certificate in accounting, 1942-1946; 3 item(s) Bulletins for 1942/43, 1944/45-1945/46
    - Extension Teaching, 1915-1920; 6 item(s) Announcements for 1915/16-1919/20
  - Graduate Studies in Geography, 1925-1953; 17 item(s) Announcements for 1947/48-1948/49, 1952/53
    - Geography, 1925-1933; 6 item(s) Announcements for 1925/26-1926/27, 1929/30-1932/33
    - Division of Geology and Geography, 1939-1947; 8 item(s) Announcements for 1939/40-1946/47
  - University Reports, 1934-1935; 2 item(s) Reports for 1934 & 1935
  - School of Architecture, 1896-1968; 62 item(s) Announcements for 1896/97; 1900; 1916/17-1917/18; 1921/22-1939/40-1945/46; 1947/48-1960/61; 1963/64-1967/68
    Architecture -- Study and teaching.
    - Evening Courses in Architecture, 1943-1958; 13 item(s) Bulletins for 1943/44, 1946/47-1957/58
    - Courses in Urban Planning, 1960-1961; 1 item(s) Bulletin for 1960/61
  - Columbia University Professional Accounting, 1943-1944; 1 item(s) Bulletin for 1943/44
  - School of Dramatic Arts, 1946-1956; 9 item(s) Bulletins for 1946/47-1947/48 Announcements for 1949/50-1955/56
    Drama -- Study and teaching.
  - School of General Studies, 1947-1979; 22 item(s) Bulletins for 1947/48-1963/64, 1965/66, 1969/70, 1971/72-1972/73
    - School of General Studies American Language Program, 1973-1979; 5 item(s) Bulletins for 1973/74-1978/79
  - Graduate Faculties, 1957-1970; 14 item(s) Bulletins for 1957/58-1965/66, 1967/68-1969/70
    - The Graduate Faculties Newsletter, 1964-1967; 2 item(s) Newsletters for May 1964 and May 1967
  - Lamont Geological Observatory, 1964-1968; 3 item(s) Bulletins for 1964/65, 1966/67-1967/68
  - Seth Low Junior College, 1928-1936; 8 item(s) Announcements for 1928/29-1935/36
    Junior colleges
  - College of Physicians and Surgeons, 1895-1978; 227 item(s) Announcements for 1895/96-1896/97, 1899/1900, 1901/02-1946/47, 1948/49, 1950/51-1954/55, 1956/57-1961/62, 1963/64-1966/67, 1971/72-1972/73
    - Report of the Dean of the Faculty of Medicine, 1924-1955; 20 item(s) Reports for 1947, 1949-1955
      - Report of the Dean of the School of Medicine, 1924-1946; 12 item(s) Reports for 1924-1925, 1927-1931, 1935-1937, 1940, 1946
    - The DeLamar Institute of Public Health, 1927-1945; 18 item(s) Announcements for 1927/28, 1929/30-1944/45 Revised Announcement for 1940/41
    - Postgraduate Courses in Clinical Medicine, 1938-1968; 11 item(s) Postgraduate courses in Clinical Medicine for Practitioners 1940/41-1941/42, 1953/54 Postgraduate courses in Clinical Medicine given at Montefiore Hospital 1943/44 Postgraduate courses in Clinical Medicine given at the Mount Sinai Hospital 1943/44 Bulletins for 1964/65-1967/68
      - Courses in Graduate Clinical Medicine for Practitioners, 1938-1940; 2 item(s) Announcements for 1938/39-1939/40
    - Psychoanalytic Clinic for Training and Research, 1944-1968; 24 item(s) Bulletins for 1944-1945, 1946/47-1967/68
    - School of Nursing, 1939-1978; 25 item(s) Announcements for 1939/40-1957/58, 1959/60-1962/63, 1965/66, 1977/78
    - School of Public Health and Administrative Medicine, 1945-1974; 31 item(s) Announcements for 1955/56, 1957/58-1959/60, 1961/62, 1964/65, 1966/67-1968/69
      - School of Public Health, 1945-1974; 11 item(s) Announcements for 1945/46-1953/54 Interim Academic Bulletin 1973/74 Booklet 12/1974
      - Preliminary Announcement of a Course in Hospital Administration, 1945-1946; 1 item(s)
      - Institute of Nutrition Sciences, 1961-1969; 5 item(s) Bulletin for 1961/62, 1965/66-1968/69
    - Programs in Physical Therapy and Occupational Therapy, 1941-1977; 24 item(s) Bulletins for 1974/75, 1976/77
      - Courses in Physical Therapy and Occupational Therapy, 1961-1974; 6 item(s) Bulletins for 1961/62-1962/63, 1964/65-1965/66, 1967/68, 1973/74
      - Courses for Physical Therapists/Occupational Therapists, 1951-1959; 8 item(s) Bulletins for 1951/52-1958/59
      - Courses for Technicians in Physical Therapy/Occupational Therapy, 1945-1951; 4 item(s) Bulletins for 1945/46-1946/47, 1948/49, 1950/51
      - Programs of Professional Courses Occupational Therapy/Physical Therapy, 1943-1945; 2 item(s) Bulletins for 1943/44-1944/45
      - Occupational Therapy, 1941-1943; 2 item(s) Bulletins for 1941/42-1942/43
    - New York Post-Graduate Medical School, 1941-1947; 12 item(s) Announcements of Short Courses for Specialists for 1941/42-1946/47
      - Department of Dermatology and Syphilology, 1941-1947; 6 item(s) Announcements for 1941/42-1946/47
  - Annual Report of the President and Treasurer, 1896-1964; 54 item(s) Reports for 1902-1933; 1936-1946
    - President's Annual Report, 1896-1902; 8 item(s) Reports for 1896-1901 Abridged edition for 1902
    - A Report from the President: a discussion of finances and a program for the next six years, 1961; 1 item(s)
    - Financial report, 1962-1964; 2 item(s) Reports for 1962/63 and 1963/64
  - Report of the Acting President of Columbia University, 1946-1948; 2 item(s) Reports for 1946 and 1947-1948
  - Report of the Treasurer, 1949-1955; 7 item(s) Reports for 1949-1955
  - New York School of Social Work, 1934-1974; 77 item(s) Bulletins for 1934/35-1936/37; 1938/39-1943/44; 1945/46-1971/72; 1973/74
    - New York School of Social Work Summer Institutes, 1934-1955; 19 item(s) Bulletins for Summer Quarter for 1934, 1936 Summer Quarter and Seminars for 1939-1940 Summer Quarter and Institutes for 1941-1945 Summer Institutes for 1946-1955
    - Report of the Dean, 1939-1965; 19 Linear Feet Reports for 1939, 1941, 1944, 1947-1948, 1951-1965
    - Alumni Conference Number, 1939-1941; 2 item(s) Bulletins for 1939, 1941
    - The Mind of Social Work, 1964
  - School of Law, 1914-1973; 81 item(s) Announcements for 1914/15-1959/60; 1961/62-1966/67; 1971/72-1972/73
    - Report of the Dean of the School of Law, 1928-1959; 22 item(s) Reports for 1928-1946; 1954. 1957, 1958/59
    - Graduate Studies of the School of Law, 1954-1969; 11 item(s) Bulletins for 1954/55-1957/58; 1959/60-1961/62; 1965/66-1968/69
  - School of International Affairs and the Regional Institutes, 1925-1973; 73 Linear Feet Bulletins for 1959/60-1962/63; 1964/65; 1966/67-1968/69; 1970/71; 1972/73
    - International Relations and International Law, 1925-1938; 7 item(s) Bulletins for 1925/26-1927/28; 1929/30-1931/32 and 1937/38
    - Latin American Studies, 1941-1945; 2 item(s) Announcements for 1941/42, 1944/45
    - Russian Institute, 1946-1959; 12 Linear Feet Announcements for 1946/47-1947/48, 1949/50-1958/59
    - School of International Affairs, 1946-1959; 8 item(s) Announcements for 1946/47-1949/50; 1951/52; 1956/57-1958/59
    - European Institute, 1950-1959; 8 item(s) Announcements for 1950/51, 1952/53-1958/59
    - East Asian Institute, 1950-1959; 5 item(s) Announcements for 1950/51-1951/52, 1954/55, 1957/58-1958/59
    - Center of Pakistan Studies, 1951-1952; 1 item(s) Announcement for 1951/52
    - Turkish Studies, 1952; 1 item(s) Announcement for 1952
    - Near and Middle East Institute, 1952-1958; 3 item(s) Announcements for 1956/57-1957/58
      - Near and Middle East Studies, 1952-1953; 1 item(s) Announcement for 1952/53
    - East Asian Studies, [1962]; 1 item(s) Rec'd Nov. 14, 1962
    - Center for Israel and Jewish Studies, 1953-1968; 9 item(s) Announcements for 1956/57-1957/58, 1961/62-1962/63, 1964/65-1967/68
      - Center of Israeli Studies, 1953-1954; 1 item(s) Announcement for 1953/54
    - Program on East Central Europe, 1955-1959; 4 item(s) Announcement 1955/56-1958/59
    - Report on Publications: 1964 and 1965, 1964-1965; 1 item(s)
    - International Fellows Program, 1967-1968; 1 item(s) Description for 1967/68
  - Graduate School of Journalism, 1916-1971; 54 item(s) Announcements for 1916/17-1917/18, 1922/23-1946/47; 1948/49-1961/62; 1963/64-1967/68; 1970/71
    - Report of the Dean of the Graduate School of Journalism, 1936-1946; 7 item(s) Reports for 1936-1941; 1946
  - School of Library Science, 1952-1968; 14 item(s) Bulletins for 1952/53; 1954/55-1958/59; 1960/61-1967/68
  - Division of Mathematical and Physical Science, 1911-1946; 33 item(s) Announcements for 1911; 1913/14; 1915/16-1917/18; 1919/20; 1921/22; 1923/24-1927/28; 1930/31-1945/46
    - Courses in Mathematical Statistics, 1943-1948; 5 item(s) Announcements for 1943/44-1947/48
  - Graduate School of Arts and Sciences, 1972-1977; 3 item(s) Bulletins for 1972/73, 1975/76-1976/77
  - The College of Pharmacy, 1923-1967; 40 Linear Feet Announcements for 1923/24-1958/59, 1960/61-1966/67
  - Division of Philosophy, Psychology, and Religion, 1900-1947; 30 item(s) Announcements for 1900/01, 1905/06, 1910/12, 1917/18, 1919/20, 1921/22-1939/40, 1941/42-1946/47
  - Division of Modern Languages and Literatures, 1903-1946; 35 item(s) Announcements for 1903/05, 1916/17-1917/18, 1919/20, 1921/22-1945/46
    - Graduate Courses in Modern Languages Summer Session, 1933-1939; 7 item(s) Announcements for 1933-1939
  - Department of Optometry, 1915-1954; 30 item(s) Courses in Practical Optics for Optometrists for 1915/16 Courses in Optics and Optometry Announcements for 1917/18, 1922/23 Professional Courses in Optometry Announcements for 1926/27-1941/42, 1943/44-1951/52 Department of Optometry Announcements for 1952/53-1953/54
  - Miscellaneous publications, 1897-1973; 19 item(s)
    - Columbia University [pictures of the various buildings], 1897-1927; 3 item(s) Publications for 1897, 1901 Views of Columbia University 1927
    - By-Laws, Statutes, and Charters, 1901-1916; 4 item(s)
      - By-Laws and Rules of Order of the Trustees, 1901; 1 item(s)
      - Statutes as revised and adopted June 6, 1892, with amendments to February 3, 1902, 1 item(s)
      - Statutes as revised and adopted to take effect July 1, 1905, 1 item(s)
      - Charters and Statutes with amendments to April 3, 1916, 1 item(s)
    - Columbia University syllabus of a collegiate course of thirty lectures on Shakespere [sic] by Frederick Henry Sykes, 1903; 1 item(s) Extension syllabi, series A, no. 1
    - Afternoon and evening course of study preparatory for the professional examinations for Certified Public Accountant of the State of New York, 1932-1933; 1 item(s)
    - Report of the Secretary of Appointments, 1933-1942; 4 item(s) Reports for 1933, 1936-1937, 1942
    - Directory Number, 1940-1941; 1 item(s) for the sessions 1940/41
    - Courses in Urban Development Housing Planning, 1947-1948; 1 item(s)
    - Handbook of Information, 1948-1950; 1 item(s) Handbook for 1948/50
    - French universities and their pursuit of freedom, 1954; 1 item(s)
    - The Role of Trustees of Columbia University, 1957; 1 item(s)
    - Who Rules Columbia: original 1968 strike edition, 1 item(s) Published by North American Congress on Latin America
    - Columbia College Tomorrow: a special report prepared by The Association of the Alumni of Columbia College, 1969; 1 item(s)
    - Oral history: 25th anniversary report, 1973; 1 item(s)
  - Courses in Religion, 1927-1933; 6 item(s) Announcements fo 1927/28-1932/33
  - Department of Music, 1916-1957; 19 item(s) Announcements for 1916/17-1917/18, 1922/23-1936/37, 1952/53, 1956/57
  - Teachers College, 1891-1972; 175 item(s) Circular of information for 1893/94-1895/96, 1897/98-1901 Annual reports, extracts for 1894/95 Handbook for 1898/99 Announcements for 1901/02-1919/20, 1921/22-1936/37, 1939/40-1960/61, 1962/63-1971/72 Preliminary Announcement School of Practical Arts for 1912/13 Announcement for School of Practical Arts for 1912/13, 1914/15, 1921/22-1925/25 Bulletin for Department of Nursing and Health, School of Practical Arts 1915/17; "Teachers College, founded in 1888 and chartered by the Regents of the University of the State of New York on January 12, 1889, became by an agreement dated March 22, 1898, a part of the educational system of Columbia University."--Teachers College Announcement 1901-1902, p. 15.
    Teachers colleges
    - Report of the President, 1891-1899; 4 item(s) Bound with Announcements: Reports for 1891, 1895/96, 1898, 1899
    - A brief sketch of the early history of Teachers College, 1899; 1 item(s) by Grace H. Dodge
    - Report of the Dean, 1900-1948; 39 item(s) Reports for 1900-1914, 1916-1918, 1920-1925, 1927-1932, 1934-1936, 1939-1941, 1946-1948
    - Teachers College Music Department, 1901-1902; 1 item(s)
    - Horace Mann School, 1910-1911; 1 item(s)
    - In honor of Edward Lee Thorndike on his twenty-fifth anniversary as professor in Teachers College, 1926; 1 item(s)
    - The Lincoln School of Teachers College, 1929; 1 item(s)
    - New College for the Education of Teachers, 1934-1938; 5 item(s) Bulletins for 1934/36-1937/38
      - New College Bulletin, 1937; 1 item(s)
      - New College for the Education of Teachers Notes, 1938; 1 item(s) Number 1, May 1928
    - The Advanced School of Education, 1935-1936; 1 item(s)
    - Report of the President, 1949-1962; 8 item(s) Reports for 1949-1954, 1955/56, 1961/62
    - Annual report, 1954-1966; 12 item(s) Reports for 1954/55-1965/66
    - Teachers College Summer Term, 1960-1970; 8 item(s) Announcements for 1961-1962, 1965-1970
    - A report of a project entitled: Teachers College looks to the future of educational administration, 1959; 1 item(s)
    - Horace Mann-Lincoln Institute of School Experimentation, 1962-1965; 3 item(s) Annual reports for 1962/63-1964/65
    - English language teaching in the lycees, colleges and ecoles normales of Guinea, 1963; 1 item(s)
    - Report of a contract education project in India, 1964; 1 item(s)